## LEIF HUHN

Chattanooga, TN 60660 leif.n.huhn@gmail.com (415) 583-5685

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Site-reliability / Tools & Automation / DevOps engineer with over twenty years of experience in a wide variety of technologies and platforms. Strengths in managing apps running in large Kubernetes clusters in AWS EC2 and other clouds. Knowledge of Docker best practices and experience with Python, Go, and build systems. Particular strengths with troubleshooting complex systems.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wish Software Engineer III 2019 - current

REMOTE San Francisco, CA

- · Troubleshot multi-threaded legacy applications running multiple pods on Kubernetes.
- · Participated in on-call rotation for wish.com. Prepared post-mortems for outages. Tracked action items to improve stability and resiliency.
- · Created a self-service system to maintain PagerDuty services leveraging Git and Terraform.
- · Had fun teaching and getting to know junior coworkers.
- · Helped others transition to remote work. Contributed to the team environment of camaraderie.
- · Conducted many interviews for roles throughout the engineering org.
- · Tech lead during onboarding process of dozens of contractors working on wish.com monolith. Troubleshot blockers related to security restrictions and other issues with development environment.
- · Maintained the Docker containers running our largest services.
- · Upgraded the OS running wish.com for SOX compliance.
- · Ported monolith and its platform to ARM architecture for speed and cost savings.
- · Packaged and contributed to open source developer tools in Go.
- · Converted Gitlab pipelines to be multi-stage, making them more efficient and easier to understand.
- · Moved engineer onboarding process from a manual process to a repeatable automated process.

#### CenturyLink Cloud

2015 - 2019

Senior Lead Software Developer

REMOTE Bellevue, WA / St. Louis, MO

- · Managed cloud services in both AWS and CenturyLink cloud.
- · Used SaltStack to manage Linux, Hadoop, HBase, Zookeeper, Kafka, and Elastic Search.
- · Deployed Consul in multi-datacenter mesh in order to support application failover.
- · Used Bash and Go scripting for various system administration purposes.
- · Created a virtual firewall product for CenturyLink's cloud using NSX Edge firewalling.
- · Migrated features from a monolithic control portal to microservices running on Kubernetes.

### Riverbed Technology

2010 - 2015

Team Lead

San Francisco, CA

- · Mentored junior coders.
- · Conceived of, collaboratively designed, and oversaw development of automation to greatly simplifying the process of adding new hardware into the lab.

- · Created system to power down unused testing machines reducing environmental impact and expense.
- · Troubleshot various DHCP, TFTP, and PXE networking problems.
- · Troubleshot problems with internal appliance manufacturing, including bugs in the unreleased product, bugs in the build system, hardware problems, user error, networking problems, service outages, etc.
- · Made OO design decisions for future direction of testing codebase.

#### Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

2003 - 2010

System Administrator

Berkeley, CA

- · Maintained critical infrastructure (mail, web, DNS, NFS, MySQL, iptables, RAID, LVM, and ssh).
- · Managed remote servers for multiple law firms.
- · Transitioned away from legacy 32-bit systems to allow processing of larger datasets.
- · Evaluated server workloads and made purchasing decisions.
- · Used Nagios to provide 24/7/365 monitoring of critical services.
- · Automated backups.

#### Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

2001 - 2003

Web Developer

Berkeley, CA

- · Developed Model-View-Controller web framework with a MySQL backend tailored for the specific needs of the company.
- · Created websites to allow hundreds of paralegals from around the country to work together to interview thousands of plaintiffs in large class action lawsuits.
- · Oversaw and trained junior web developers.

# Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission

1999 - 2000

Tallahassee, FL

Web Developer

· Developed data heavy client side web applications and managed IIS.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

· Python, C/C++, Go.

· Unix Scripting: POSIX sh, bash, expect, zsh

· Kubernetes, Docker, KVM

 $\cdot$  SQL, NoSQL databases

· Salt, Terraform, Linux, Git, cgroups

· DNS

· Graphite, Grafana, Prometheus

- · RAID, LVM, NFS
- · tcpdump, Wireshark
- · MacOS, homebrew
- · AWS EC2, ECR, S3
- · Gitlab
- · LATEX

#### **EDUCATION & HOBBIES**

- $\cdot$  University of California, Berkeley, CA
  - Bachelors Degree in Physics
- · Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL
  - Completed University Honors Program. GPA: 3.9
- · Studying Rust through on-line exercises
- · Conversational in American Sign Language, some knowledge of Spanish and French